# JACK MUMFORD

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research focuses on the challenge of advancing explainable AI systems that can provide rationales for their outputs. I am interested in building machine learning that is logically coherent and investigating the extent to which such learning can accommodate effective human-computer interaction in order to engender greater trust in the output. In particular I examine the intersection of neural networks (subsymbolic) and argumentation semantics (symbolic), resulting in neural argumentation networks (NANs) that learn in a logically coherent manner according to argumentation principles.

# **EDUCATION**

## 2016 - 2017 MSc in Intelligent Systems

King's College London, Department of Informatics, UK

Distinction

## 2012 - 2016 BSc in Mathematics

The Open University, School of Mathematics and Statistics, UK

1st Class (Honours)

#### RESEARCH

## 2017 - PhD candidate in Computer Science

King's College London, Department of Informatics, UK

Thesis: Exploring the connections between argumentation and neural networks in producing data-driven decision making.

Supervisors: Professor Simon Parsons (School of Computer Science, University of Lincoln), Dr Elizabeth Black (Department of Informatics, King's College London) and Dr Isabel Sassoon (Department of Computer Science, Brunel University London).

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## 2017 - Graduate Teaching Assistant

King's College London, Department of Informatics, UK

Taught small and large tutorial groups as well as computer lab practical sessions for undergraduate and masters level modules:

• Machine Learning • Data Mining • Software Measurement & Testing • Introduction to Robotics • Simulation & Data Visualisation.

Additional duties: coursework marking; moderation, invigilation and second marking of examinations.

## 2014 - 2016 GCSE and A-Level Mathematics Tutor

West Midlands, UK

Self-employed in providing private one-one tuition for secondary school students studying for examination at GCSE and A-Level mathematics. Developed tailored lesson plans, marked homework, provided learning goals and provided relevant feedback in order to develop the students' confidence in the subject and their own abilities.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**#** 2012 - 2014

Programme Co-ordinator/Operations Co-ordinator

# University of Warwick, Warwick Business School, UK

I had responsibility for the successful administrative delivery of undergraduate modules (as Programme Co-ordinator) and distance learning masters-level content (later as Operations Co-ordinator). Both roles involved:

• Carefully monitoring student enquiries and providing timely responses by email, telephone and face-to-face • Support preparation and running of departmental open days • Analysing core statistics with Excel, Access and Outlook; and producing reports based upon departmental performance data.

The role of Operations Co-ordinator also required production of invoices for necessary materials. The role of Programme Co-ordinator also involved meeting with prospective students and their parents to explain and advocate the courses offered by the department.

**#** 2010 - 2012

Customer Services Officer

# HSBC Bank, Stratford-upon-Avon, UK

The role entailed driving the quantity of sales and the quality of service within a challenging target assessed team environment. Additionally I was accepted onto the internal fast track Promotion Scheme (Talent Pool). My duties included:

• Facilitating transactions from International Payments to more complex matters such as Personal Lending • Securing appointments and providing financial service via telephone • Auditing of work and organisation of branch procedural checks (following my promotion to act an authorised Signatory of the bank) • Flexibly supporting smaller branches of the bank, in various locations, in a supervisory role as and when required.

#### AWARDS & GRANTS

2019 Nominated for King's Education Award (King's College London)

## 2019 Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award (Dept. of Informatics, King's College London)

## 2017 - 2020 PhD studentship (EPSRC)

## 2017 Prize for the best overall performance on the MSc in Intelligent Systems (Dept. of Informatics, King's College London)

#### ACADEMIC SERVICE

🗎 2020 - Department of Informatics TA Liaison Committee (King's College London)

TA Representative

## 2019 - Online Handbook for Argumentation in Artificial Intelligence (OHAAI)

Co-Founder & Editor

## 2019 - Argumentation Reading Group (King's College London)

Co-Founder & Member

2016 - 2017 Department of Informatics Postgraduate Staff Student Liaison Committee (King's College London)

Student Representative & Co-chair (from 2017)

#### OTHER SKILLS

| Programming | knowledge |
|-------------|-----------|
| Languages   |           |

Python, MATLAB, Java, HTML, LaTeX.

English (fluent), French (intermediate), Spanish (intermediate).

## SCIENTIFIC TALKS



• Building Neural Argumentation Networks (NANs) - automating the learning of attack relationships from data. Seminar for the Reasoning and Planning Group, Department of Informatics, King's College London, UK.



- Building Neural Argumentation Networks (NANs) automating the learning of attack relationships from data. Presentation at the Argumentation Workshop, Imperial College London, UK.
- Argumentation Machine Learning. Seminar for the Argumentation Reading Group, King's College London, UK.
- Attack learning using a feed-forward neural network. Seminar for the Argumentation Reading Group, King's College London, UK.
- Calculating Dung semantics attack-relations using a feed-forward neural network. Presentation at the London Argumentation Forum, Imperial College London, UK.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

# Published papers:

1. J. Mumford (2020). "Crafting neural argumentation networks". Online Handbook of Argumentation for AI: Volume 1. arXiv:2006.12020 [cs.AI].

# Papers being prepared for submission:

- 2. J. Mumford, I. Sassoon, E. Black and S. Parsons. "Deriving argumentation framework attack-relations from data using a feed-forward neural network". Being prepared for submission to *Artificial Intelligence*, expected submission date July 2020.
- 3. J. Mumford, I. Sassoon, E. Black and S. Parsons. "On the complexity of mapping attacks to argument acceptability data". Being prepared for submission to *Thirty-Fifth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence*, expected submission date September 2020.

## Edited books:

4. Online Handbook of Argumentation for AI: Volume 1 (2020). arXiv:2006.12020 [cs.AI].